Chris POSKITT

School of Information Systems
Singapore Management University (SMU)
80 Stamford Road
Singapore 178902

Email: cposkitt@smu.edu.sg



Summary Statement

Chris Poskitt is an Assistant Professor of Information Systems (Education) at Singapore Management University (SMU), where he is a member of the Research Lab for Intelligent Software Engineering. Prior to SMU, he held research and teaching positions at ETH Zurich, Switzerland, and the Singapore University of Technology and Design. His research broadly addresses the problem of engineering correct and secure software/systems, towards which he has co-developed techniques for testing/defending cyber-physical systems, tools for analysing execution models of concurrency APIs, and logics for reasoning about the correctness of graph-rewriting programs. His research interests span software engineering, formal methods, cybersecurity, and computer science education.

Education

PhD, University of York, Great Britain, 2014
Bachelor of Science, University of York, Great Britain, 2009

Academic Appointments

Assistant Professor of Information Systems (Education), School of Information Systems, SMU, Jan 2020 - Present

Lecturer & Research Fellow, Singapore University of Technology and Design, Singapore, Jan 2018 - Jan 2020

Research Fellow, Singapore University of Technology and Design, Singapore, Mar 2016 - Jan 2018

Postdoctoral Research Scientist, ETH Zurich, Switzerland, Jan 2013 - Jan 2016

Awards and Honors

Vice-Chancellor's Teaching Award, University of York, 2011

Professional Memberships

Member, IEEE, 2020

Member, Formal Methods Europe, 2015

Associate Fellow of the Higher Education Academy (AFHEA), Higher Education Academy, UK, 2011

RESEARCH

Research and Project Areas

Software Engineering
Formal Methods
Cybersecurity
Computer Science Education

Publications

Journal Articles [Refereed]

Deriving invariant checkers for critical infrastructure using axiomatic design principles, by YOONG, Cheah Huei; PALLETI, Venkata Reddy; MAITI, Rajib Ranjan; SILVA, Arlindo; POSKITT, Christopher M.. (2021). *Cybersecurity,* (Accepted)

A semantics comparison workbench for a concurrent, asynchronous, distributed programming language, by CORRODI, Claudio; HEUSSNER, Alexander; POSKITT, Christopher M.. (2018). *Formal Aspects of Computing*, 30 (1), 163-192. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00165-017-0443-1 (Published)

SafeGPU: Contract- and library-based GPGPU for object-oriented languages, by KOLESNICHENKO, Alexey; POSKITT, Christopher M.; NANZ, Sebastian. (2017). *Computer Languages, Systems and Structures*, 48 68-88. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cl.2016.08.002 (Published)

Hoare-style verification of graph programs, by POSKITT, Christopher M.; PLUMP, Detlef. (2012). *Fundamenta Informaticae*, 118 (1-2), 135-175. https://doi.org/10.3233/FI-2012-708 (Published)

Conference Proceedings

Towards systematically deriving defence mechanisms from functional requirements of cyber-physical systems, by YOONG, Cheah Huei; PALLETI, Venkata Reddy; SILVA, Arlindo; POSKITT, Christopher M.. (2020). *Proceedings of the 6th ACM Cyber-Physical System Security Workshop (CPSS 2020), Taipei, Taiwan, 2020 October 6,* (pp. 11-22) Taipei, Taiwan (Virtual): ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/3384941.3409589 (Published)

Active fuzzing for testing and securing cyber-physical systems, by CHEN, Yuqi; XUAN, Bohan; POSKITT, Christopher M.; SUN, Jun; ZHANG, Fan. (2020). *Proceedings of the 29th ACM SIGSOFT International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis, ISSTA 2020, New York, July 18-22,* (pp. 14-26) Virtual Event, United States: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/3395363.3397376 (Published)

Securing Bring-Your-Own-Device (BYOD) programming exams, by KURNIAWAN, Oka; LEE, Norman Tiong Seng; POSKITT, Christopher M.. (2020). *Proceedings of the 51st ACM Technical Symposium on Computer Science Education (SIGCSE 2020), Portland, OR, USA, March 11-14,* (pp. 880-886) Portland, OR, USA: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/3328778.3366907 (Published)

Learning-guided network fuzzing for testing cyber-physical system defences, by CHEN, Yuqi; POSKITT, Christopher M.; SUN, Jun; ADEPU, Sridhar; ZHANG, Fan. (2019). *Proceedings of the 34th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering (ASE 2019),* (pp. 962-973) San Diego, CA, USA: IEEE. https://doi.org/10.1109/ASE.2019.00093 (Published)

Learning from mutants: Using code mutation to learn and monitor invariants of a cyber-physical system, by CHEN, Yuqi; POSKITT, Christopher M.; SUN, Jun. (2018). 2018 39th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (S&P 2018): San Francisco, May 21-23: Proceedings, (pp. 648-660) Piscataway, NJ: IEEE. https://doi.org/10.1109/SP.2018.00016 (Published)

Anomaly detection for a water treatment system using unsupervised machine learning, by INOUE, Jun; YAMAGATA, Yoriyuki; CHEN, Yuqi; POSKITT, Christopher M.; SUN, Jun. (2017). 17th IEEE International Conference on Data Mining Workshops ICDMW 2017: 18-21 November, New Orleans, LA: Proceedings, (pp. 1058-1065) Los Alamitos, CA: IEEE Computer Society. https://doi.org/10.1109/ICDMW.2017.149 (Published)

Towards learning and verifying invariants of cyber-physical systems by code mutation, by CHEN, Yuqi; POSKITT, Christopher M.; SUN, Jun. (2016). *Proceedings of the 21st International Symposium on Formal Methods (FM 2016), Limassol, Cyprus November 9-11,* (pp. 155-163) Limassol, Cyprus: Springer. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-48989-6_10 (Published)

An interference-free programming model for network objects, by SCHILL, Mischael; POSKITT, Christopher M.; MEYER, Bertrand. (2016). *Proceedings of the 18th International Conference on Coordination Models and Languages (COORDINATION 2016), Heraklion, Crete, Greece, June 6-9,* (pp. 227-244) Heraklion, Crete, Greece: Springer. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-39519-7_14 (Published)

A graph-based semantics workbench for concurrent Asynchronous programs, by CORRODI, Claudio; HEUSSNER, Alexander; POSKITT, Christopher M.. (2016). *Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Fundamental Approaches to Software Engineering (FASE 2016), Eindhoven, Netherlands, April 2-8,* (pp. 31-48) Eindhoven, Netherlands: Springer. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-662-49665-7_3 (Published)

Contract-based general-purpose GPU programming, by KOLESNICHENKO, Alexey; POSKITT, Christopher M.; NANZ, Sebastian; MEYER, Bertrand. (2015). *Proceedings of the 2015 ACM SIGPLAN International Conference on Generative Programming: Concepts and Experiences, Pittsburgh PA, USA, October 26-27*, (pp. 75-84) Pittsburgh, PA, USA: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/2814204.2814216 (Published)

The AutoProof Verifier: Usability by non-experts and on standard code, by FURIA, Carlo A.; POSKITT, Christopher M.; TSCHANNEN, Julian. (2015). *Proceedings 2nd International Workshop on Formal Integrated Development Environment (F-IDE 2015): Oslo, Norway, June 22,* (pp. 42-55) Waterloo, NSW: Open Publishing Association. https://doi.org/10.4204/EPTCS.187.4 (Published)

Towards practical graph-based verification for an object-oriented concurrency model, by HEUSSNER, Alexander; POSKITT, Christopher M.; CORRODI, Claudio; MORANDI, Benjamin. (2015). *Proceedings of the 1st Graphs as Models (GaM) 2015 workshop, London, April 10-11,* (pp. 32-47) London, UK: https://doi.org/10.4204/EPTCS.181.3 (Published)

Towards rigorously faking bidirectional model transformations, by POSKITT, Christopher M.; DODDS, Mike; PAIGE, Richard F.; RENSINK, Arend. (2014). *Proceedings of the 3rd Workshop on the Analysis of Model Transformations (AMT 2014)*, (pp. 70-75) Valencia, Spain: http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-1277/8.pdf (Published)

Verifying monadic second-order properties of graph programs, by POSKITT, Christopher M.; PLUMP, Detlef. (2014). *Graph transformation: 7th International Conference, ICGT 2014, York, July 22-24, Proceedings,* (pp. 33-48) Berlin: Springer. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-09108-2_3 (Published)

Using contracts to guide the search-based verification of concurrent programs, by POSKITT, Christopher M.; POULDING, Simon. (2013). Search Based Software Engineering: 5th International Symposium, SSBSE 2013, St. Petersburg, Russia, August 24-26, Proceedings, (pp. 263-268) Berlin: Springer. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-39742-4_22 (Published)

Applying search in an automatic contract-based testing tool, by KOLESNICHENKO, Alexey; POSKITT, Christopher M.; MEYER, Bertrand. (2013). Search Based Software Engineering: 5th International Symposium, SSBSE 2013, St. Petersburg, Russia, August 24-26, Proceedings, (pp. 318-323) Berlin: Springer. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-39742-4_31 (Published)

Verifying total correctness of graph programs, by POSKITT, Christopher M.; PLUMP, Detlef. (2012). Selected revised papers from the 4th International Workshop on Graph Computation Models (GCM 2012): Bremen, Germany, September 28-29, (pp. 1-20) Utrecht: EASST. https://doi.org/10.14279/tuj.eceasst.61.827 (Published)

Verification of graph programs, by POSKITT, Christopher M.. (2012). *Graph transformations: 6th International Conference, ICGT 2012, Bremen, Germany, September 24-29: Proceedings,* (pp. 420-422) Berlin: Springer. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-33654-6_30 (Published)

A Hoare calculus for graph programs, by POSKITT, Christopher M.; PLUMP, Detlef. (2010). *Graph Transformations: 5th International Conference, ICGT 2010, Enschede, the Netherlands, September 27-October 2, Proceedings,* (pp. 139-154) Berlin: Springer. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-15928-2_10 (Published)

Hoare logic for graph programs, by POSKITT, Christopher M.; PLUMP, Detlef. (2010). *VSTTE 2010 Workshop Proceedings: Edinburgh, August 16-19,* (pp. 1-11) Zurich: ETH. https://doi.org/10.3929/ethz-a-006860117 (Published)

Research Grants

Singapore Management University

Towards Practical Attestation Solutions for Countering Advanced Attacks to Industrial Control Systems, NSoE DeST-SCI Grant Call, National Satellite of Excellence - Design Science and Technology for Secure Critical Infrastructure, Co-PI (Project Level): SUN Jun, 2019, S\$939,180

A two-track approach to CPS Reconnaisance: causal-graphs and axiomatic design, NSoE DeST-SCI Grant Call, National Satellite of Excellence - Design Science and Technology for Secure Critical Infrastructure, Co-PI (Project Level): Chris POSKITT, 2019, S\$447,172

Other Institutions

Contracts and Search for Finding Faults (Conseff), Division II: Mathematics, Natural and Engineering Sciences, SNSF Bertrand MEYER, 2014, CHF329,378

TEACHING

Teaching Areas

Enterprise Solution Development Web Application Development II

Courses Taught

Singapore Management University

Undergraduate Programmes:

Digital Business - Technologies and Transformation

Enterprise Solution Development

Web Application Development I

Web Application Development II

Other Institutions

Capstone, Undergraduate, Singapore University of Technology and Design

Concepts of Concurrent Computation, Masters, ETH Zurich

Digital World, Undergraduate, Singapore University of Technology and Design

Mathematical Foundations of Computer Science, Undergraduate, University of York

Seminar: Research Topics in Software Engineering, Masters, ETH Zurich

Software Verification, Masters, ETH Zurich

THESES AND DISSERTATIONS

Theses and Dissertations Supervised

Other Institutions

Supervisor, "Modelling and Verifying an Object-Oriented Concurrency Model in GROOVE", Dissertation by Claudio CORRODI, ETH Zurich, 2015

Theses and Dissertations Assessed

Other Institutions

Co Supervisor, "Automatic Defense and Analysis of Cyber-Physical Systems", Thesis by Yuqi CHEN, PhD, Singapore University of Technology and Design, 2019

Committee Member, "Learning Invariants and Assertions", Thesis by Pham Hong Long, PhD, Singapore University of Technology and Design, 2019

Co Supervisor, "Seamless Heterogeneous Computing: Combining GPGPU and Task Parallelism", Thesis by Alexey KOLESNICHENKO, PhD, ETH Zurich, 2016

OTHER ACADEMIC AND PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

Invited Seminars, Talks and Lectures

Facilitating an effective mixed-mode class - Tips and strategies, 16 Oct 2020. SMU Centre for Teaching Excellence (CTE) Seminar, Singapore

Securing and Trusting Cyber-Physical Systems, 11 Feb 2019. CIS Department Seminar, Melbourne, Australia

Learning from Mutants: Using Code Mutation to Learn and Monitor Invariants of a Cyber-Physical System, 18 May 2018. Programming Systems Group Seminar, San Diego, United States of America

A Graph-Based Semantics Workbench for Concurrent Asynchronous Programs, 04 Nov 2015. Dagstuhl Seminar no. 15451: Verification of Evolving Graph Structures, Wadern, Germany

Hoare-Style Verification for GP 2, 03 Nov 2015. Dagstuhl Seminar no. 15451: Verification of Evolving Graph Structures, Wadern, Germany

UNIVERSITY SERVICE

Singapore Management University

Committee Member, SMU Futures Thinking Group: Imagining SMU 2035, Jun 2020 - Present

Other Institutions

Committee Member & Global Exchange Programme Representative, ISTD Undergraduate Committee, Singapore University of Technology and Design, Jan 2019 - Dec 2019

Committee Member, Niklaus Wirth 80th Birthday Symposium, ETH Zurich, Sep 2013 - Feb 2014

EXTERNAL SERVICE PROFESSIONAL

Reviewer Conference Paper, SIGCSE 2021, 2021

PC Member, 12th Working Conference on Verified Software: Theories, Tools, and Experiments (VSTTE 2020), 2020

PC Member, 1st IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automation of Software Test (AST 2020). 2020

PC Member, 2nd International Workshop on Artificial Intelligence and Industrial Internet-of-Things Security (AloTS 2020), 2020

Reviewer Journal Article, Computers & Security; Cybersecurity; Journal of Logical and Algebraic Methods in Programming, 2020

Reviewer Conference Paper, ICFEM 2020, SIGCSE 2020, 2020

PC Member, 10th International Workshop on Graph Computation Models (GCM 2019), 2019

PC Member, 1st International Workshop on Artificial Intelligence and Industrial Internet-of-Things Security (AloTS 2019), 2019

PC Member, 12th International Conference on Graph Transformation (ICGT 2019), 2019

Reviewer Conference Paper, ATVA 2019, CONCUR 2019, and TASE 2019, 2019

PC Member, 4th ACM Workshop on Cyber-Physical Systems Security and PrivaCy (CPS-SPC 2018), 2018

PC Member, 14th International Conference on integrated Formal Methods (iFM 2018), 2018

Reviewer Journal Article, Computer Languages, Systems and Structures; Frontiers of Information Technology & Electronic Engineering, 2018

Reviewer Conference Paper, ESOP 2018, 2018

Reviewer Conference Paper, FormaliSE 2017, FMICS/AVOCS 2017, and ICECCS 2017, 2017

Reviewer Conference Paper, APSEC 2016, FSCD 2016, GCM 2016, and ICGT 2016, 2016

Reviewer Journal Article, Theoretical Computer Science, 2016

Reviewer Conference Paper, GCM 2015, ICGT 2015, 2015

Reviewer Journal Article, Empirical Software Engineering; Science of Computer Programming, 2014

Reviewer Conference Paper, AVoCS 2014, ICGT 2014, SAC-SOAP 2015, 2014

Reviewer Journal Article, Science of Computer Programming, 2013

Reviewer Conference Paper, GCM 2012, ICGT 2012, 2012

Reviewer Conference Paper, GCM 2010, ICGT 2010, 2010